sports in general, the NFL in specific,
you always look for an extra edge. What
gives you the motivation?
And in this episode of Defending the
Kingdom, we're going to give you three
new Chiefs that fit right into this
file. Because what will something to
prove for all three of these guys and
something to prove in the NFL can be
very, very interesting and a great
motivating factor. This episode, like
them all, is brought to you by
Ticketmaster. There's so many awesome
events uh coming up in the next several
months throughout the Chiefs Kingdom
that Ticketmaster would be your place to
go.
>> Mahomes in the pocket will step up.
HE'LL SCRAMBLE. 10 FIVE Momes diving.
TOUCHDOWN
Kansas City.
>> Hi everyone. I'm Mitch Holtus, voice of
the Kansas City Chiefs along with senior
team reporter of the Kansas City Chiefs,
Matt McMullen. kind of fired up today
because because what seemed like of like
let's just fill in some topic and fill
in a show to me has turned into
something else. Particularly when I look
at the three free agents we're going to
talk about that have been in the league
the Chiefs signed in that so-called
second wave of free agency. This isn't
the crazy days of the first 24 hours or
48 hours. This is kind of a little bit
of an aftershock. Although one name will
be very familiar. The other two may not
be as much, but uh something to prove.
Did you ever have something to prove?
>> You've been in the NFL now. Okay. So,
you've been involved with professional
sports for how long?
>> Professional sports since uh 2014.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Which I would have been a junior
in college.
>> When did you ever face either you can't
do it or you felt like I'm going to
prove to somebody I can do this? Well,
in college when I told people I wanted
to work in sports and originally I
wanted to be like a sports writer.
>> This is at Missou by the way.
>> Yeah. Uh I would just get the Well,
everyone wants to do that. You have to
find like a real job. Like everybody
wants to do that. You're not going to be
able to do that. That motivated me
>> for sure. Yeah. I mean, every single
internship I had because I worked in
minor league baseball for a while and
then eventually u Major League Baseball
and now the Chiefs obviously uh every
step along the way it was h everybody
wants to do that. there's no way you're
going to be able to stand out amongst
everybody else. And I think that
motivated me to prove everybody wrong.
Yeah.
>> Was there a was there a professor or a
couple people that said that or is there
a face that you see? Well, so there'd be
like, yeah, I like teachers, uh, you
know, other students, but also there was
one person I remember because my sister
moved out to California years ago
because she wanted to pursue like an
acting career. And, uh, we did like
Thanksgiving out in California with some
people that she had met. And one of her
new friends moms was trying to like
dissuade me entirely from a sports
career. Like, don't do it. That's not a
real job. Like, you're not going to find
success. It's not worth it. Over and
over again. And like it was like the
worst Thanksgiving ever. But it like
stuck with me. I'm like, I'm going to
prove this lady wrong, you know? So,
anyway, here we are.
>> And it still motivates you, right?
>> It sure does. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Been there, too. Uh, a couple
different things. One was to had had
been doing college ball for a long time.
It was voice to Kate, right? And
involved there and kind of created a lot
of their marketing department in sports.
But people were saying, man, you you
could you have the level to be a
professional uh announcer. I'd looked at
it and thought, okay. So, I've kind of
put my toe in the water. There was a
baseball job that might be very close to
here, uh, the television job where I was
told, "This looks really good. Looks
like you're the guy." And in 24 hours,
it changed.
>> Oh, man.
>> I kid you not. Then there was the uh,
it'll be in the book that you'll help me
write, the trip to Chicago, and that was
the interview at WGN
to be either Bears or Cubs. They were
looking at both ways, and and so I was
highly recommended. There was like 300
people that were up for this job. This
looks really good. Now, getting there
was a whole another story. That'll be
the story in the book because it was one
of the coldest days ever. And my car
froze on the interstate. Uh that I'm
just going to tell you that's a whole
another story. Point is, I got to the
altar, but no wedding.
Minnesota Vikings. Okay. Get to the
final five of the Minnesota Vikings.
It's in the St. Paul Pioneer Press,
Minneapolis Tribune. They had the
finalists. Didn't make it.
>> Could have had a touchdown. Midnot.
>> Yeah. But Paul Allen's got it now. He's
good.
>> Yeah, he's good.
>> The point is that no, I can do this and
I'm going to keep fighting and I'm going
to get there. And then at my first job
out of college, was not in the pro
ranks. It was doing high school in 35
high schools, junior college sports. And
I was selling advertising so I could eat
uh with my new wife who I still have. It
was awesome.
But the owner of that station was not a
great guy.
>> Okay. And he was going to make me sign a
non-compete. And I go, I'm not going to
sign that. And he goes, you'll never
amount to anything.
>> He said that to you?
>> He took me to a hotel in this town and
took I thought he's going to kill me.
He's going to wipe me out. Right. just
said it's the scene in uh The Godfather,
right? You're in the back seat like take
the canoli, leave the gun, and uh just
verbally.
>> I'm seriously I'm like 23 years old and
I go, "He's going to kill me." He goes,
"You'll never amount to anything."
>> I still see that face.
>> Yeah, I bet.
>> So,
>> where's that guy at now? Does he listen
to Chiefs games on the radio?
>> He might be. That's a whole another
story. Okay. He might be watching this
podcast.
>> Might be. Hello to you, sir.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you for watching. Uh anyway,
there are motivations that will carry
players,
uh people in other forms of life, but
these three we're going to talk about
today, when you dive into them, you
really see that they could become
something with the Kansas City Chiefs in
one way, shape, or form. And it's
because they have something to prove.
Now, before we get into that, let's go
around the world. What do we have?
>> Yes, sir. I got two for you today.
>> Um, and these are both like out in the
wild ones, like real people.
>> Ta Thornton might be wearing too, right?
>> I guess so. Yeah,
>> he's going to wear too like
>> I'm glad Taekquin's back. We talked
about that on our last episode, but I
mean, think about last year whenever we
needed a spark, like a big play. He was
that guy last year and excited for him
to come in and
>> have that confidence to to be even more
of a guy
>> this year. So,
>> you talked about the Giants game. I'm
not sure we win that game if that
anyway.
>> Oh, yeah. Well, the Broncos game in
Denver. The reason we were in it was
because of him.
>> Y
>> uh the Eagles game, I believe he had a
big play. Like could go on and on.
Excited for Taekwon.
>> And most football guys now want single
digits. Linemen know they can't have it.
But everybody else, DBs, wide receivers,
quarterbacks, running backs. We have a
former college quarterback that's
helping shoot this. They all want single
digits. So, it looks like Taekquin,
since Joshua Williams is gone, might be
number two.
>> What if we went the other way? Remember,
uh the quarterback at Michigan that was
like 98 or something?
>> Oh, yeah. Tom Harmon.
>> Yeah.
>> Go back go back in the old days. It was
like, why is 87 a quarterback? Yeah,
>> I love it.
>> Love it.
>> Um and then some of these, we're just
going off the rails here. I was doing
some offensive line draft breakdowns
earlier and uh Spencer Fono from Utah
wears 55. Yeah, it's weird
>> as a tackle.
>> Yeah, right. Tackle 55.
>> That's what a center is supposed to
wear,
>> right? Um okay. Anyway, around the world
two for you today. Uh shout out to
Mario. Uh, so Ellie and I were walking
back from lunch uh, downtown on Saturday
and Mario came up and said hi. So, shout
out to you, Mario. Thanks for saying hi.
>> Uh, and then shout out to Madison. Uh,
those of uh, you out there that know me
well know that I love Chili. It's one of
my favorite establishments. Love going
to Chili's. You know, if you're ever
worried about the economy, go to Chili.
You'll not be worried about the economy.
>> Pretty good.
>> Uh-huh. I'm actually a Chili's member,
so I get free chips and salsa. Like, I'm
like a ticket holder at Chili.
>> I got this. Yeah.
>> You have a sweet? I should. I'd love to.
>> I thought I was being really funny, too,
because um
>> Ellie got me like a Chili's hat for
Christmas as like a gag gift, and I wore
the hat to uh this dinner the other
night,
>> and while I'm sitting there in my
Chili's hat, Madison comes up and says,
"Hi." So, shout out to you, Madison.
Thanks for uh not making fun of me for
being a total goober at Chili's, but
it's great.
>> Yeah. Shout out to Madison. Shout out to
Mario.
>> I've been in a food coma once because of
that chips and salsa.
>> This keeps coming.
>> Keeps coming. Thin chips and salsa. I
don't know what's in it.
>> Uh I've got one real quick. Um cuz we
just went on our little sbatical spring
with my awesome wife and we tried we've
done this for our 40 plus years of
marriage. As crazy as our lives are,
we've tried to sur u preserve time. It
was just four days, maybe five, where
you date each other again. You get away
and it's awesome. We're walking along
the beach and this guy goes, "Hey, like
you're that you're that guy.
>> You can't escape."
>> I go, "Yeah, what's going on?" He's
like, "You were at our spring break
location three years ago."
>> Can't make it up. This is a long way
away where we were in the States, but we
three years ago were in St. Louis. We
took our granddaughters over to St.
Louis for a little kind of station
thingy real quick. And they were there
at the same spot.
>> No way. No, I couldn't believe it
either. Don't know the cat's name, but
he's like, "You were there three?" I'm
like, "Okay, somebody's following
somebody here." So, anyway, I just
thought, "Okay, can't make that up."
>> Did he know like who you were with the
Chiefs and everything?
>> Yeah, he's from He's from Gotcha. How
funny.
>> Hey, you guys three years ago were like,
you know, like same spring break
location. Now you're here and this
location is probably what, 1800 miles
away from St. Louis.
>> You going to start coordinating?
>> No, we won't do that. We don't
coordinate with anyone. Actually, we try
to go hide.
>> Yeah.
>> So, anyway, uh but these three free
agents, something to prove. And we're
going to jump right into Kater Coo
because who and we faced this guy uh in
the game in Germany uh back in 2023 as a
Dback for the Miami Dolphins. Now, I've
learned in 33 years of the NFL, there
are some things that motivate players,
especially on a second contract, a
second spin around that. And here's
Kater's two that fit into the category
that we're talking about here. One, he
played division two football. Now,
Texas&M Commerce, this is in the
norththeast end of the metro, but not
far. This is getting in Patrick
Mahomes's range, not quite to the Piny
Woods, but up in there. And he went to
Ulis High School in Trinity, which is
well known. But Kedar played division 2
football. Now, since then, East Texas&M,
which is now called, has gone to FCS,
uh, basically won AAA in a good
conference, the Southland Conference. At
the time, they were division two. We
have seen both of us division two
players, division three NIA players make
it in the NFL, but they've got an extra
little push to them.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Okay. U Quinn Miners, right, got to put
out even an opponent um who's
outstanding that was a division three
player.
>> Yeah. uh
>> Wisconsin Whitewater
>> Whitewater and he's, you know, we know
all about him being a Denver Bronc
offensive lineman. Kater played division
two football. The second thing would be
coming back from injury. Kater even
though he's an undrafted free agent.
There's another one, three actually. Kar
fits three here. Division two player,
undrafted free agent. How many times
Cooper McDonald, right? We consider and
look guys who are undrafted free agents.
They're showing you didn't draft me.
Watch me make it in this league. Watch
me become a player. Kater has done that.
three coming back from injury,
devastating ACL injury in training camp
last year after this guy. And you're
going to you got some great stats on
him, but he played 88% of the snaps as
an undrafted free agent rookie. And this
is the same secondary that had Javon
Holland and Xavier Howard. Yeah.
>> Right. These guys weren't awful. Then we
saw him in Germany uh in 85% of the
snaps. And so he's played a lot of
football, has the ACL goes down, and now
he's starting over, but he's got
division two, undrafted free agent.
Watch this. Watch me come back from an
ACL.
>> So you and I have both had opportunities
to speak at the rookie dinner over the
years, which I always think is one of
the coolest events that we do here.
>> It's awesome.
>> So obviously, we bring in our draft
class immediately after the draft for
rookie mini camp, but it's also all of
our undrafted free agents and the 60
plus tryyout players that are here. 95%
of which will not be here after those
three days, but they're all invited to
the rookie dinner. And it's so much fun
to speak to those guys and to remind
them, hey, you're in a place that's
going to give you an opportunity. And
you can see like in some of the players
out in the group, you can see in their
eyes like, I'm not going to waste this.
And Kater for Miami was one of those
guys. It's so cool to think that he came
in with nothing promised, like no
guarantees. And not only did he make the
team back when he first got u signed to
the Dolphins, he was like a a starter, a
contributor for them. Uh to the point
where if he hadn't gotten hurt last
year, I think he'd be in line for
probably a pretty decent contract. Now
>> he has to prove it again, right? But
look at what he did before the injury.
>> A couple things stand out to me. So
first, experience. 38 career starts for
the Dolphins from 2022 through 24. This
isn't a guy that you're just projecting,
saying, "Hey, if he had more
opportunities, I think he could really
contribute." He played for them and
played well. Uh the scheme fit is also
interesting. Mostly a slot corner for
them, which frankly we could use. Uh
especially with Trent McDuffy no longer
being here. Uh Kedar is a player with a
ton of experience playing the slot and
playing it really well. And not just as
a cover guy, but also as a blitzer off
the edge. Did a little bit of that uh
with the Dolphins and Ste Bagnolo
obviously values that uh really
productive. So, 28 passes defensed uh
during his time with Miami. Um he was
one of just 12 players to record at
least eight pass breakups in each season
from 2022 through 2024. And this is a
fun one. It's like an advanced metric.
In 2024, he ranked sixth among all
corners in terms of yards allowed per
coverage snap. So,
>> this guy's a really solid slot corner
that had a bad break last year with uh
the ACL injury, but uh you trust your
doctors, trust your trainers. If they
feel like he's ready to go, um hopefully
sooner than later, uh he can get out
there and and hopefully pick right up
where he left off.
>> The other thing that translates from, I
don't care what level of college you
play, FCS, FBS, Division 2, 3, NIA, that
translates to the pros is a DB that gets
marks. And I mean, uh, things happen. If
you look at what he did, Kater Coo at
East Texas A&M, five interceptions, four
force fumbles, three fumble recoveries,
two defensive touchdowns, and a block
kick. All right. Well, in the pros,
what's Okay, three interceptions, two
force fumbles. You mentioned the pass
defense, two fumble recoveries. Here's
the other thing of why he's a scheme
fit. I love the slot. Slot blitzer
covers in the slot. Not afraid. The dude
has got a lot of courage. In three
years, 180 tackles. Who does that sound
like? The corners that have played here.
>> Yeah.
>> Since Spags has been here. The other one
that gets that got my attention, we
talked about that he played against us
in Germany. You know, the other game he
played against us, the minus 28
windchill game.
>> Yeah, he sure did. He was in his rookie
year played the windchill game against
us minus 28 windchill when it seemed
like most of the Dolphins really didn't
want to be here in that 26-7 glorious
wildcard victory on the way to Super
Bowl 58.
In that game,
uh Kedar had seven tackles
and was one of the leaders on for both
teams in that game in a minus 28
windchill game. That's all I got to
know.
>> Yeah. give the guy a chance. And I
didn't know much about him. I went back
and looked at my boards right from those
games and I thought, "Okay." Then I dug
into him and I thought, "No, he's got
something to prove."
>> Yeah, I think you're right. And one
other thing that stands out to me is,
you know, team reporters talk, right?
Like we'll chat about certain players
that we like.
>> You're like scouts, right?
>> Yeah. Well, particularly when players go
from team to team. So I did this with
McDuffy. like uh myself and Stu Jackson
with the Rams were chatting about Trent
McDuffy and what to expect with them,
some storylines, stuff like that. Uh
Travis with the Dolphins reached out to
me immediately and said, "You guys are
going to love Kater." So that's all I
need to know. I'm fired up about this
guy.
>> That's so cool. So when you're with
>> like you'll say like Gabe from Liberty,
the guy that was a quarterback kind of
wide receiver. What? Yeah,
>> exactly.
>> Same deal.
>> Tell me about him. Right.
>> Tell me about him. The second one. So,
all right. Think Kate or Kohou. The
Chiefs might get more here than you
think. All right.
>> And particularly while we're remaking
our secondary a little bit here where
don't have Jaylen in town, don't have
Trent.
>> We're going to give null Williams an
opportunity. I presume Christian Fulton
is in this mix, but adding a player like
Kar who can play that slot, you feel
good about plugging him in there,
assuming he's healthy, that's a big
deal. Or if you draft a corner, wink
wink nod nod that you could either at
nine or 29 or 40 or 74 who could start
from day one snap one. Then you have
confidence in your nickel to play a
caterer who's got
>> a lot of experience in that nickel
position. And he was used in the nickel
position the way the Chiefs use their
nickels.
>> Exactly.
>> Not all nickels are used the same.
>> No.
>> Okay. So, here's where Kedar uh
something to prove, checks three of the
boxes. Played division two, wants to
prove he can play with the big boys,
already has. Two, undrafted free agent.
Want to prove that he can play with the
big boys, already has. Three, I'll come
back from this ACL that he has not, but
he's going to. Yeah. All right. So,
fired up about him. The other one too of
three is Amari de Marcado. And when we
signed him, I thought, you know, I
remember we played him in the preseason,
played him some, and I thought
>> he had a big play against us in the
preseason.
>> He did. It was awesome. That's what kind
of caught my attention. Like, who's this
guy? And when you look at Amari de
Marcato, you TC Horn Frog fans that are
Chiefs Kingdom fans remember him. But
here's one of the boxes that he checks
in the I'm going to prove it to you. I
can play in the NFL Jo player. Now, I
started, as I told you in the st outset
of this podcast, in the junior college
ranks, and I've seen many guys go from
the junior college ranks to National
Football League stardom. Okay. And the
Jay-Hawk JO, which is one of the premier
junior college leagues uh in the
country, is right under her nose here in
the Cheese Kingdom. Same NEO&M in Miami,
Oklahoma. It's right there. All right.
He plays at Saddleback Community
College.
>> I knew you'd love that.
>> Oh, yeah. I'm all about this. I'm all
about it. And the fact that he went to
high school in LA, he goes to Saddleback
Community College and then plays at TCU.
Five years at TCU after one year at
Saddleback. Both these guys had played a
long time in college. Same thing with
Kedar. But Amari D Mato to me has
something to prove uh because he's a Jo
player. Oh, wait a minute. See if this
sounds familiar. Undrafted free agent.
was not drafted uh out of TCU and became
a player for Arizona. All right. Third
thing he has to prove is something
happens in your career that seemingly
defines you and you're going that does
not define me. And that was the fumble
at the goal line last year at the end of
what would have been a 72 yard touchdown
run that Amari gets credit for a 71yd
run
but let go of the ball before the end
zone. We seen Jonathan Ganon the
sideline U exchange. Amari's devastated
by the play.
You think he wants to something to
prove? He goes that ain't me. Because he
said that ain't me. and actually played
really good football after that. Saying
that one play will not define me. That
to me excites me about Amari de Marcato
>> 100%. And you know holding on to the
ball and crossing the goal line that's
an easily correctable thing. I doubt
that ever happens to him ever again. Um
it's one of those things where you make
a mistake and you say I'm going to make
sure I never do that again. The
difficult part of that play is the 71
yard run and he can handle that part.
Don't change that. Right. And I mean the
dude's explosive. Mhm.
>> Didn't have a lot of carries in Arizona,
only 126, but he made the most of every
single one of them. He averaged 6.5
yards per carry during his time there.
Uh, a lot of big plays, obviously.
Ripped off 20 runs of double- digit
yardage during his career, doing so on
15.9%
of his carries. He doesn't have enough
carries to qualify in that category in
terms of like the the leaders over the
last three seasons, but if he did, he
would lead the NFL in that category. Uh,
for comparison's sake, Devon Han, of
course, maybe the most explosive back in
football right now, he's at like 15.6%.
So, not a lot of carries, but on those
carries certainly made the most of them.
And, uh, yeah, holding on to the
football, I'm sure, will be a priority
for him. I doubt he ever makes that
mistake again. I'm not even worried
about that at all. The thing I'm most
excited about though with this guy
beyond just the explosiveness, the pass
pro. He can pass protect. uh he spent at
least 18% of his total snaps in each of
the last three seasons in pass
protection, allowing just eight
pressures on 104 snaps. For guys like
this, we always try to compare him to
Jerick McKinnon. Jerick McKinnon is like
the gold standard. Jerick was an
explosive player, a spark plug player,
but he was an awesome pass protector.
Like awesome. And I think about uh Amari
De Marcado. He kind of fits that mold
for me. So really fired up about this.
Uh, you know, Brett said that we were
going to get more explosive at running
back. He wasn't lying. We got Kenneth
Walker. We got Amari Demarcato. I'm
excited about it.
>> And the Pass Pro thing is really
exciting because I go back I I'm a
little bit like Tim Terry now. I go back
and look at his draft analysis. Sure. He
was not drafted coming out of TCU. And
the big knock on him was pass protection
and look what he's done in his career in
the NFL. The other thing is you
mentioned the touches. How many fumbles
do you think he had with the Arizona
Cardinals with 176 touches?
>> Guessing not many.
>> One. The only one was the one at the
goal line.
>> Wow. So,
>> and that was that was self-forced. It
wasn't like he Yeah, that's that's good
news right there.
>> Another one. In five years at TCU, one
fumble.
>> Okay. You're saying, "Well, it wasn't
that many touches. He's a third down
back." Yeah, that's perfect. Here's my
next favorite stat about Amari D.
Marcato. Who was the best defense last
year in the NFL?
Uh, oh gosh, now I'm on the spot. I've
wiped last year clean from my mind.
Denver.
>> Yeah, they're right there. But I put
Seattle right in there.
>> Oh yeah, for sure. It's Seattle. That's
the answer. Yeah.
>> The longest play Seattle gave up all
year was to Amari D. Marcato. At least a
run, I should say, of 55 yards.
>> Wow. Against the Seattle Seahawks. I've
watched it 10 times. And it's a
legitimate run against a great defense.
The longest run the Chiefs had last year
was 35 yards by Xavier Worthy.
>> Yeah, we had three runs of 20 or more
yards last year.
>> Oh my gosh. The year before going to the
Super Bowl was Isaiah Pacheco at 34.
>> Now you got to go all the way back to
October 1 of 2023 when Pop Pacheco had
the 48- yard New Jersey turnpike run
right on Sunday Night Football against
the Jets in his front of his home crowd.
Immari de Marcado in 23 had a 49 yard
touchdown against San Francisco. Pretty
good defense.
>> Yeah.
>> In 24 he had a 53 yard touchdown run
against Chicago. A 41 yard run against
the Rams. The fif the aforementioned 71
and 55 yard runs last year. All of those
runs would have classified as the
longest run by a Kansas City Chief the
last three years.
>> Wow.
>> So I get fired up. I get chills down my
spine talking about the potential of
Amari D Marcato. Jo player, check the
box. All right, young undrafted free
agent, check the box. Something to
prove. And third, a really motivating
factor. He doesn't want that play that's
all over the reels of the NFL season of
25 to be the defining uh play for him.
And I'm going to bet a hundred bucks
right now to anybody that's listening or
watching this podcast that he will
redeem himself from that play. I can't
wait to see this kid work.
>> Yeah, I'm with you. And we're both
really excited about Bashard Smith
moving forward. I think Bashard showed a
lot at the end of last year. Uh really
solid in that Raiders game
>> and explosive to fit your explosive
theme.
>> Exactly. So now you look at this running
back room. We have Ken Walker. All
right. One of the best running backs in
all of football. You have Amari De
Marcado who we've been talking about who
not a lot of touches but every time he
touched it seemed to go for 30 yards.
Right. and a young player in Bashard
Smith who we believe in. That's a really
good group. That's an explosive group.
And I truly believe like I've talked
about for weeks on our podcast. Adding
an explosive element to the running game
is going to change everything for this
offense.
>> I think really in many ways we were
playing with like both hands tied behind
our back at times last year because our
running game was not explosive and our
play action passing game as a result was
not very effective. Well, you have to
respect this running game now. You have
to respect it because any of these guys
at any moment could take the ball for a
45 yard touchdown and we just didn't
have that last year.
>> Matt and I at an undisclosed location in
downtown Kansas City have an annual
lunchon just the two of us.
>> Uh that is the who's going to be the
third down back lunchon after Jerick Mc
you talk about the gold standard. It's
why I love getting Sama JP Ryan and I
wept when we lost him. Okay. and we get
to the Super Bowl. Uh because of him,
>> Amari de Marcado,
>> yeah,
>> can be this guy. And what watch him run
draws and screens
>> because he's patient. He gets it. He
understands it. So a third down back,
what do they have to do? They better
pass protector. You're not going to have
that job. You already covered that.
Draws, screens, provide a big play. And
these draws and there was one third and
five play I looked at against the Rams.
The 41 yard is a third and five play.
They did it thinking, "Well, they're
gonna throw. It's a throwing formation."
And then he turns it into a 41 yard run
against a good defense. I I'm more fired
up about this than I thought I was going
to be.
>> You know how uh Kelse and Greg Olsen and
KD started tight end U.
>> Yeah.
>> I think I think McKinnon and Per Ryan
should start third down backu.
>> I know where we're going to have the
banquet.
>> Where's that?
>> Where we have our at our summit
location.
>> Our summit location. We'll invite all
third down backs around the league. And
then we'll have our third down uh back
of the year award.
>> If you want to be a third down back,
come to Kansas City and come to our
summit.
>> We love it. We value third down backs on
defending the kingdom. So should you.
>> Just as well I can't win in my fantasy
draft with him. Now you win football
games with him.
>> Sure do.
>> All right. The third one you all know
about. uh because uh he's been all over
uh shoot social media and regular media
ever since he was a five-star player in
the state of Georgia, Kennesaw, Georgia.
Uh he signs at Georgia. Then he goes to
Ohio State. Kind of a controversial
move, but then at Ohio State did
incredible things. The 11th pick by Matt
Naggie and the Chicago Bears in Matt's
last year in 2021. We're talking about
Justin Fields here. And Justin Fields is
now a Kansas City Chief. And that's one
of those where people go, "What? Justin
Fields is a Kansas City Chief?" All
right. What does he have to prove? A
couple things. One, he's not just a
running quarterback because when you're
on the same line with Lamar Jackson and
Michael Vic and you're the only three on
that line, that's pretty good. And which
is what he did as his rushing total when
he was with the Bears.
two,
even as a high drafted player, remember
we talked about undrafted free agents,
but as a high drafted player, I'm going
to prove that I can play to that pick
and be in the role here as a terrific
vice president to Patrick Mahomes. And
so that's where we're at with Justin
Fields.
>> I think one of the reasons, one of the
many reasons we have been so successful
since Coach Dre got here is the
stability that he provides. There is
stability here for players to come in
and to reach their full potential. I
think that's why a lot of times you have
players that didn't work out elsewhere,
they come here and it works because
there is stability. If you look at
Justin Field's career, there has just
not been a ton of stability for him
wherever he's been. He has not had an
opportunity in my opinion to really
reach his full potential at any of his
stops just because of the lack of
infrastructure at times in place from an
offensive standpoint.
Things have snowballed over time in
those places and just couldn't climb out
of it because that stability wasn't
there.
>> Yeah,
>> that stability is here and if he is
going to reach his full potential, it
will be here and I'm excited about that.
If there's one time in his career that I
think he really put it together, it was
in Pittsburgh. So, in Pittsburgh,
because Russell Wilson was hurt, he
began the season as the Steelers
starter. They went four-2 in the games
that he started uh in the only two games
he lost, lost by a combined six points,
and he played well in those games. Had a
quarterback rating over 90. Uh kept him
obviously in every game. Really
competitive. And then when Wilson came
back, Fields went back to the bench.
Kind of another example of how there
wasn't even stability there in
Pittsburgh. So, I think for Fields, all
the talent in the world, that's obvious.
And at times, we've seen flashes of it.
I think he just needs a coaching staff
and a stable environment for him to go
out there and thrive. And he's going to
have that opportunity during the
offseason training program to get us
through this time. And then, uh, when
Mahomes is back, you have a veteran,
experienced, dynamic player behind him
that, uh, you can count on to go in
there and and win a game if he needs to.
And also even when Mahomes is healthy,
there's things you could do with Justin
Fields because of his incredible
athleticism. So yeah, I'm excited about
this and I'm excited for Justin because
I think here he has a chance to truly
become the player that he is and some
thing he has he has eight NFL records.
Justin Fields has eight National
Football League records. What he did in
2022 when he ran for almost,50 yards uh
was phenomenal. 78 yards against Miami.
That's an NFL record for a quarterback
running the ball. But it's also been the
injuries, Matt. If you go back through
his NFL career in 21, his rookie year,
he's humming along pretty good with NES.
So, going okay. Going okay. Ribs, ankle.
>> Okay. Flat tire. 22. We talked about in
22, the high productivity year, ankle,
shoulder. The big one is in 23. In fact,
he lost at Kansas City that year. We
played him. Um, he had one game where
he's 16 out of 16 against Denver.
>> That was the That was the first game
that Taylor was at. That was a crazy
day.
>> And that's I think that's in the notes
here. So, that's another reason Justin
Fields was I got to go back. Maybe
Taylor will come back to my game. Uh,
the right thumb injury
got him that year. Like that right thumb
injury took Justin Fields off the track.
And so then he goes to Pittsburgh.
Chicago gives up on him basically. They
move on. Go to Caleb Williams. then in
Pittsburgh, but he had an abdominal
injury in Pittsburgh. Uh, and then with
the Jets last year, a concussion knee
injury. Every year there's been
something. So, another box to check is I
can do this. I can do this. I've proven
I can do I've got eight NFL records.
I'll be a good soldier in stability and
then but I can play to that 11th pick
and I'm going to prove to you that I can
stay healthy and do it. I I think those
are all reasons Justin Fields is got a
reason to do uh to be a good quarterback
here in Kansas City.
>> And I was talking about how Brett wasn't
messing around with getting us more
explosive. Well, Justin Fields is pretty
explosive as well. Uh you can find ways
to have him impact the game even when
Patrick is healthy. And I'm excited
about that.
>> There will be plays. They're going to be
in there at the same time. Do you don't
think they won't there won't be. There's
a little Steelers in this. I'm the
biggest proponent of a dual quarterback
set. I love it.
>> Yes.
>> You know, Pat will line up in the
Wildcat direct snap. He goes out at wide
receiver. One of these days we'll throw
him a pass.
>> Yes. He wants it badly. I think
>> maybe Fields will throw it to him.
>> There we go.
>> Cuz now if you put Fields in that
Wildcat role and Pat's the Pat's the
wide receiver. I'm just telling you, I
got a feeling it's somewhere Andy Reid
called Mike Tomlin and goes, "Hey, you
know what? What do you think if we try
this?"
>> Yeah, I'm into that plan.
>> I am too. Be kind of fun. Do you think
we'll see it in OTAAS?
>> Um, maybe.
>> We'll see.
>> And then we'll file that one away until
week won't be out there in OTAAS, right?
Probably.
>> That's true. That's true.
>> Training camp.
>> Training camp. We'll see it.
>> We'll see it.
>> Yeah. And then and then file it away and
we won't see it again for three months
and then we'll be like, "Oh, yeah. There
it is."
>> I thought this was going to be a
Defending the Kingdom episode that we're
just gonna fill in the gap. Do a week
and we may have Kelsey next week, right?
>> Hope so.
>> But hey, let's glad. what are we going
to do to fill it in? And then I started
getting into these guys. And then you
and I started to talk. And then I
started to realize that every one of
these guys
has something to prove.